Guide to the Benjamin Brookshire and M. Benson Lassiter Papers, 1852-1931
Rare Book, Manuscript, and Special Collections Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Benjamin Brookshire and M. Benson Lassiter papers 1852-1931
Rare Book, Manuscript, and Special Collections Library, Duke University
Brookshire, Benjamin W.
6.0 Linear Feet 651 Items
Brookshire was a physician, of Pekin (Montgomery Co.), N.C.
Correspondence and other personal, business, and land papers, including ledgers, prescription books, bills and receipts. Many of the papers belonged to or relate to M. Benson Lassiter. Chief coverage is for 1860-1890. Includes letters from Brookshire's relatives in North Carolina giving information on farming and farm life during the early 1900s; and letters from family members who settled in Kansas and the Indian Territory of Oklahoma during the 1890s, regarding land claims. Other letters deal with teachers and teaching in North Carolina schools and academies of the 1880s, notably the Bingham School in Orange County and the Oakdale Academy at Oakdale.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the Rare Book, Manuscript, and Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Benjamin Brookshire Papers were acquired by the Rare Book, Manuscript, and Special Collections Library in 1950 and 1955.
Biographical Note
Brookshire was a physician, of Pekin (Montgomery Co.), N.C.
Collection Overview
Correspondence and other personal, business, and land papers of a physician of Gray's Cross Roads in Randolph County and of Pekin and Mt. Gilead in Montgomery County. There is some information on lands in Indian Territory during the 1890s and farm life in North Carolina during the early 1900s. The volumes include ledgers and other accounts, and a prescription book, which also contains a list of voters in Cheek's Creek Township, 1890. A few letters to Brookshire's son, Charles E. Brookshire, refer to education at the Bingham School in Orange County and Oakdale Academy in Oakdale, North Carolina, in the 1880s.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Brookshire, Benjamin W.
Lassiter, M. Benson
Bingham School (Orange County, N.C.)
Oakdale Academy (Oakdale, N.C.)
Physicians -- Correspondence
Farm life -- North Carolina
Public lands -- Oklahoma
Education -- North Carolina
Teachers -- North Carolina
Contents of Collection
- Volumes, 1860-1900, (7 volumes)
  - Daybook, 1866-1884 (Volume L:5230)
  - Invoice book, 1866-1871 (Volume L:5231)
  - Ledger, 1860-1875 (Volume S:5232)
  - Ledger, 1861-1882 (Volume M:5233)
  - Ledger, 1874-1885 (Volume M:5234)
  - Ledger, 1885-1893 (Volume L:5235)
  - Prescription book, 1890-1900 (Volume M:5236)
    Also has list of voters in Cheek's Creek Co., 1890.
- Papers, 1850-1936, (3 boxes)
  - Miscellaneous financial papers, 1880s-1930s (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1852-1931 and undated, (3 folders)
  - Bills and receipts, 1850-1880s, (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Broadsides
  - Printed materials
  - Letters, 1850-1934 and undated (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1880-1936 and undated
    Financial papers, printed materials, clippings, writings, and essays.